这个城市的坏人在改变
The bad guys in this town are changing.
本字幕由ZiMuZu原创翻译  最新下载请登录www.ZiMuZu.tv
翻译 辰星晓Reginamoon   小胖纸Amy   Silence   DustD   木浅
翻译 charcie   大K   小酸奶!   草草   后期 饿得慌
时间轴 风吹来的那片云   校对&总监 草草
欢迎各位
Welcome, everyone.
世人视你们为精神病罪犯
The world sees criminal lunatics.
我看到的却是天才
I see brilliance.
哥谭新市长  西奥·盖勒文
Theo Galavan, the new mayor of Gotham!
不
No.
妈妈
Mother!
有什么遗言吗
Any last words?
我会杀了你的
I'm going to kill you.
他们要为自己的所作所为付出代价
They're gonna pay for what they've done.
你好啊  吉姆
Hello, Jim.
请你让开
Please step aside.
这是杀死你父母的凶手的名字
This is the name of the man who killed your parents...
你被捕了
You're under arrest.
不  告诉我是谁杀了他们
No! Tell me who killed them!
起床了  瞌睡虫
Hello, sleepyhead.
我母亲是个圣人
My mother was a saint!
一个人没有任何所爱  就是自由的
A man with nothing to love is free.
茜尔薇不是好人  布鲁斯
Silver is bad news, Bruce.
你要干什么
What are you doing?
住手  马龙  那人叫马龙  他叫这个
Stop! Malone! It's Malone! That's the name.
再见了  茜尔薇
Good-bye, Silver.
布鲁斯  你不能这么对我
Bruce, you can't do this.
这不像你
It isn't you.
那是你这么想
That's what you think.
但你错了
But you're wrong.
你说对我叔叔了
You're right about my uncle.
他就是大家说的那样
He's everything everyone says.
我不知道将来情况会有多糟
I don't know how bad it's gonna get.
根本没有界线
There is no line.
只有法律
There's just the law.
吉姆  你看见万丈深渊  便飞奔过去
Jim, you see an abyss, and you run toward it.
我怀孕了
I'm pregnant.
我们需要采取一切手段
We need every method at our disposal.
如果说我们什么时候应该合作
If there was ever a time for us to work together,
那就是现在了
now is that time.
哥谭需要他死
Gotham needs him dead!
想想大局
Think of the greater good.
想想哥谭
Think of Gotham.
再见了  吉姆·戈登
Good-bye, Jim Gordon.
经过对大楼的搜索
After searching the premises,
我  以及阿尔弗雷德·潘尼沃斯
I, along with Alfred Pennyworth
还有塞琳娜·凯尔
and Selina Kyle,
终于找到了被绑架者
was able to locate the abductee,
布鲁斯·韦恩
Bruce Wayne.
他当时在哪里
Where was he?
西奥·盖勒文的住处
Theo Galavan's residence.
-你们就是那时开火的吗  -是的
- That's when you opened fire? - Yes.
我们解除了由克里尔神父
We eliminated the threat
和他的手下所造成的威胁
posed by Father Creel and his men,
救回了布鲁斯·韦恩
and were able to recover Bruce Wayne.
亵渎
Sacrilege!
然后你就独自离开去找盖勒文了吗
You then left to search for Galavan on your own?
正是如此
That's correct.
你找到他了吗
Did you find him?
找到了
Yes.
西奥·盖勒文
Theo Galavan.
你被捕了
You're under arrest.
-你扣押了盖勒文吗  -没有
- Did you detain Galavan? - No.
为什么
Why not?
巴恩斯警监和瓦加斯警员赶到了
Captain Barnes and Officer Vargas arrived
并逮捕了我
and placed me under arrest.
吉姆
Jim!
你把枪放地上
Put your gun on the ground
手放在头后
and put your hands on top of your head.
那是因为这件事发生时...
That's because at the time of this incident--
大约四周前  你还是个亡命逃犯
some four weeks ago-- you were a fugitive from the law.
那是一场误会
That was a misunderstanding.
接下来发生了什么
What happened next?
奥斯瓦尔德·科波特带着两名手下赶到了
Oswald Cobblepot and two of his associates arrived,
将巴恩斯警监和瓦加斯警员打晕了
rendered Captain Barnes and Officer Vargas unconscious.
科波特和他的手下带着盖勒文逃跑了
Cobblepot and his associates escaped with Galavan.
你真的确定
Are you 100% sure
他不会再次逍遥法外吗
that he won't beat this and walk free again?
然后你就去追捕科波特和他的手下了  是吗
You then pursued Cobblepot and his men, correct?
是的  但我没找到他们
Yes, but I was unable to locate them.
你是个有良心的人  吉姆
You're a man of conscience, Jim.
你会后悔的
You'll regret this.
我有很多后悔
I have many regrets.
这件事不会占榜首的
This won't be top of the list.
之后  你便决定逃出城
At which point, you decided to flee the city
而非接受执法人员问话吗
before law enforcement could question you?
是的  对于这一点  我无法辩驳
Yes, for that, I have no excuse
只能说
other than to say
我当时很担心我未婚妻的安全
I was concerned for the safety of my  fiancée.
那天早些时候
Uh, she had informed me
她告诉我她怀孕了
earlier that day that she was pregnant.
恭喜
Congratulations.
谢谢
Thank you.
戈登警探
Detective Gordon,
你们遭遇后几小时内
within hours of your encounter,
西奥·盖勒文就被人殴打并枪击而死
Theo Galavan was found beaten and shot to death.
他被杀时  你在现场吗
Were you present at the time of his murder?
这一刻来了
Ah, well, here we are.
不  我不在场
No, I was not.
你是否有任何关于案情的信息
Do you have any information regarding the case
没有告诉我们的
that you have not shared with us?
这是为了我母亲
This is for my mother.
没有  我全盘告知了
No, I do not.
警探
Detective,
你是否参与了
did you have anything to do
西奥·盖勒文的谋杀
with the murder of Theo Galavan?
警探  请回答问题
Detective, answer the question.
你是否参与杀害了西奥·盖勒文
Were you involved in Theo Galavan's murder?
我没参与
No, I was not.
指控撤销了
Charges are lifted.
我证明了清白也恢复了职位
I'm cleared of all wrongdoing and reinstated.
我就知道他们会想通的
I knew they would see sense.
我没那么有把握
I didn't.
你说了实话  他们还能怎么样
You told the truth. What choice do they have?
是啊
Yeah.
你确定这是你想要的吗
Are you sure this is what you want?
这份工作让我们经历了那么多坎坷
After everything this job has put us through?
确定
Positive.
那有什么问题呢
Then what's wrong?
没什么
Nothing.
今天很辛苦
Long day.
你保证吗
Promise?
我保证
Promise.
巴恩斯
Barnes.
丹特
Dent.
引人入胜的故事
Captivating story.
是啊  没错
Yes, it was.
你相信他吗
Do you believe him?
我相信你的调查没有发现任何
I believe your investigation has found no evidence
犯罪行为的证据
of criminal wrongdoing.
小心
Careful.
你这语气变得像律师了
You're starting to sound like a lawyer.
有没有科波特的线索
Any leads on Cobblepot?
他众叛亲离
His men have deserted him.
现在孤身一人
He's all alone.
我们迟早能找到他
It's only a matter of time before we find him.
通
缉
奥斯瓦尔德·科波特
针对犯罪头目奥斯瓦尔德·科波特的追捕
It's now day 27 of the manhunt for crime lord
已进入第27天
Oswald Cobblepot.
哥谭市警方仍在彻查城市
GCPD officers continue to comb the city
搜寻这个他们声称
in search of the man they say
冷血杀害了饱受争议的西奥·盖勒文市长的人
killed controversial Mayor Theo Galavan in cold blood.
头号公敌仍在潜逃  我们不禁要问
With public enemy number one on the lam, the question remains,
谁在掌控哥谭的黑帮
just who is running Gotham's underworld?
把他带走
Take him away.
你好啊  布奇
Hello, Butch.
你好吗
How you doing?
你的安保措施太烂了
Your security stinks.
通常人们都想逃离这里  而不是要进来
People are usually trying to get out of this place, not in.
怎么拉着脸呢
Why so glum?
你现在是哥谭之王了
You're the King of Gotham now.
我没拉着脸
I'm not glum.
只是在思考
I'm just... thinkin'.
我责任重大
I got a lot of responsibilities.
不像你想的那么好玩吧
Not as much fun as you thought it'd be, huh?
话说  你想怎么样
What do you want, anyway?
你那么虐待我  居然还敢跑来
You got a lot of nerve showing up after what you did to me.
你凶起来就这样吗
Is that your mean face?
你能怎样  杀了我吗
What are you gonna do, kill me?
也许吧
Maybe I will.
我做的事帮你解脱了  布奇
What I did for you, Butch, is make you a free man.
如果不是我  你不可能成为老大
If it wasn't for me, you wouldn't be king.
你肯定一直是那么打算的吧
I bet that was your plan all along, huh?
你就是那么喜欢我
You're just that fond of me.
说来也怪  我是挺喜欢你
Strangely enough, I am kind of fond of you.
一般来说  我都喜欢有颜值  有脑子的人
I mean, normally, I go for handsome, intelligent men,
而不是蛮人  但是
not brutes, but...
你有一种惊人的
you have an amazing...
野性
animal vitality about you.
我比看上去要聪明多了
I'm smarter than I look.
当然了
Oh, you must be.
真风趣
Oh, funny lady.
你到底想怎么样
What do you really want?
我想成为你的犯罪同伙
I want to be your partner in crime.
寂寞了吧
Lonely, huh?
我们会成为好伙伴的
You and I would make a good team.
我现在不想找伴儿
I'm not looking for a relationship right now.
亲爱的  看看我
Honeybun, look at me.
我们有过往
We have history.
我们俩都知道  在你内心深处
And you and I both know, deep down in your heart,
无论我想要什么
that whatever I want...
也是你想要的
...you want.
各单位请注意
All units, all units.
接到报警  科尔尼大道
Reported armed abduction
三百街区附近  发生持械绑架案
near the 300 block of Kearny Avenue.
附近所有可出动的警官请回应
Any and all available officers in the area, please respond.
哥谭市警局
GCPD.
有问题吗  警官
There a problem, Officer?
这一带发生了绑架案
There's been an abduction in the area.
-太不幸了  -今晚有看到什么吗
- How awful. - Have you seen anything tonight?
有什么不寻常的事吗
Anything out of the ordinary?
没  没看到
No. Can't say that I have.
你住在这一带吗  先生
Do you live in the area, sir?
离这儿不远
Not far.
地址是什么
What's your address?
其实我是想说  我以前住在这一带
Well, what I mean to say, I used to live in the area.
我搬走了
I moved.
能请您把车后箱打开吗  先生
Would you open the back of the van, please, sir?
没问题
Sure thing.
乐意效劳
Happy to.
这什么...
What the...
哥谭
第二季  第十二集
把那俩人拉开
Hey, man, separate those two.
你来了正好
It's a good thing you're here.
昨晚碰上一个怪案
Caught a weird one last night.
就这样了  不抱一个  亲一下
That's it? No hug? No kiss?
说句"欢迎回来"
No "Welcome back"?
你配不上这朱唇
You don't deserve these lips.
在我看来  你骗到了
Way I see it, you finagled yourself
一个月的带薪长假  你个混蛋
a month-long paid vacation, you bastard.
再说了  警监在这案子上催得很急
Besides, Captain's pressing me on this case.
是吗  什么案子
Oh, yeah? What is it?
你没听说吗
You didn't hear?
昨晚  有个疯子冻住了一名警察
Last night, some psycho froze a cop.
造成死亡
To death.
冻住她
Froze her?
是啊  跟你说了很奇怪
Yeah. Told you it was weird.
来吧  尼格玛在等我们
Come on. Nygma's waiting for us.
冻住了
Frozen.
有意思
Interesting.
需要近五秒钟
It took nearly five seconds
液氮才能把这朵玫瑰冻住
to freeze this rose in liquid nitrogen.
所以呢
So?
所以  冷冻人体需要更久的时间
Well, so, it would take a human body significantly longer,
当然  要看体重和体脂含量
depending on mass and body fat, of course.
一个警察为什么会站立不动几小时
So why would a cop stand around for hours,
等着被冻住呢
waiting to get frozen?
她不会那么做
She wouldn't.
也就是说你的嫌疑人用的不是液氮
Which means your suspect wasn't using liquid nitrogen.
他用的是过冷液态氦
He was using supercooled liquid helium.
那是世界上可以最高效地
It's one of the most effective substances in the world
进行急速降温的化学物质
for rapid temperature reduction.
这种液态氢
This liquid helium,
在哪里能弄到
where do you get it?
你要来做什么
Why do you need it?
他不需要  呆瓜
He doesn't, dummy.
他只是想知道来源
He just wants to know where it comes from
我们好顺藤摸瓜找出
so we can track down the guy
速冻了我们同事的那个人
that blasted our colleague with it.
我不喜欢被人侮辱
I don't like being called names,
警探
detective.
放松  爱德
Easy, Ed.
我相信哈维只是在开玩笑
I'm sure Harvey was just being colorful.
是啊
Yeah.
我只是在开玩笑  爱德  对不起
I was just being colorful, Ed. I'm sorry.
那东西非常稀有昂贵
It's extremely rare and expensive.
我猜哥谭的制造商应该不出一两个
I can't imagine there's more than one or two producers in Gotham.
你需要的话  我可以调查一下制造商
I could research manufacturers, if you would like.
那就太好了
That would be really nice.
谢谢  爱德
Thank you, Ed.
-不走吗  -我等下就来
- You coming? - Uh, give me a minute.
听着  爱德
Listen, Ed,
我有事想跟你聊聊
there's something I wanted to talk to you about.
-企鹅  -没错
- Penguin. - Yes.
你想知道我和他的关系
You want to know the nature of my relationship with him.
-是的  -因为你担心
- Yes. - Because you're concerned
我协助并教唆了一个罪犯
I aided and abetted a known criminal.
那你帮了吗
Did you?
我在森林里发现了受伤
I found Mr. Cobblepot wounded
濒死的科波特先生
and dying in the woods.
我照料他  直至他康复
I nursed him back to health.
他欠我一条命  所以当他告诉我
He owed me his life, which is why I trusted him
他已改邪归正时我信任了他
when he said he had changed his ways.
是个无心之失
It was an innocent mistake.
抓到了
Got him!
抓到他了
We got him!
不知道又怎么了
I wonder what that is.
安静
Silence!
当自己是啦啦队的吗
What are you, a bunch of cheerleaders?
这不是游戏
This is not a game!
这是我们的工作
This is our job!
而这个  家伙
And this... specimen...
不过是个可悲的罪犯而已
this is just one sad, pathetic skell.
外面的人渣还很多
There are plenty of scumbags out there.
很多
Plenty.
所以别在这儿瞎咋呼了
So stop waving your pom-poms
去给我抓几个坏人回来
and go catch some!
想看就看吧
Yes, stare all you want.
欢呼吧
Big whoop.
你们抓到我了
You got me.
我没事
I'm cool.
挺好的
It's all good.
我说过我会抓到他  我也抓到了
I said I'd catch him. And I did.
-是  长官  -现在我们能知道
- Yes, sir. - Now we'll learn the truth
盖勒文到底发生了什么事了
of what really happened to Galavan.
好了  科波特
All right, Cobblepot.
告诉我那天晚上在盖勒文家到底发生了什么
Tell me what happened at Galavan's that night.
那天发生了不少事呢
Well, a lot of things happened.
就从你拿花瓶打晕我之后
Why don't you start with the moment right after
开始说起吧
you knocked me out with that vase.
那事我很抱歉
I'm sorry for that.
那花瓶挺精致的呢
Such an exquisite vase.
你逗笑我了
This is my amused look.
继续说
Keep talking.
我带盖勒文去河边杀掉了他
I took Galavan to the river and I killed him.
我慢慢来的
Slowly.
你承认杀人了
You confess to murder?
是的  我承认
Yes, I do.
自豪无比
Proud of it.
要知道  我不是罪犯
I'm not a criminal, you know?
我是个...
I'm just...
疯子
insane.
詹姆斯·戈登做了什么
What did James Gordon do?
你指什么时候
What did he do when?
你打昏我后  他做了什么
What did he do after you knocked me out?
他怎么跟你说的
What does he say he did?
我在问你
I'm asking you.
你有什么要说的吗
You have something you want to tell me?
没有  长官
No, sir.
科波特证实了你的说法
Cobblepot backed your story.
您是说  他说了实话
You mean he told the truth.
嗯
Yeah.
我就这么相信吧
That's what I'm gonna choose to believe.
您这么做是对的
That's the right thing to do.
很高兴你能归队
Good to have you back.
我很高兴能归队  长官
Good to be back, sir.
吉姆  我信任你
Jim, I'm trusting you.
别让我出丑
Don't make a fool out of me.
是  长官
Yes, sir.
我刚梦见你了
I was having a dream about you.
我们在海滩边的小红木屋里
We were at that little red cabin by the beach.
记得吗
Remember?
记得
I remember.
六年前的夏天
Six summers ago.
你就像个电影明星
You looked like a movie star.
你好像很累
You look tired.
工作嘛
Work.
怎么样了
How's it coming?
不错
Good, good.
进度比想象中慢  但还不错
Slower than I'd like, but good.
跟我说说
Tell me.
冻后复苏出了些问题
I'm having trouble with the reanimation.
我得找到液态氦
I need to find the correct ratio of
和甘油低温防护剂的正确比例
liquid helium to glycerol cryoprotectant.
用英语解释一下  亲爱的
Now tell me what that means in English, honey.
就是说
It means...
正如计划的那样  我可以冷冻你
I can freeze you, like we planned.
可以把你的体温降至零下128度
I can bring your temperature down to 200 degrees below zero,
这样你就不会被这个病害死了
and I can stop this disease from killing you.
但是
But?
我无法让你复活
I can't bring you back.
暂时还不能
Not yet.
但我会成功
But I will.
-对不起  -不是因为你
- I'm sorry. - It's not that.
只是想到被你拿来试验的可怜的小老鼠
I'm just thinking of all those poor mice you're experimenting on.
他们没有感觉
They don't feel anything.
我只需要点时间
I just need more time.
再多点时间就行
A little more time.
我会找到办法的
I'll find a way.
我保证
I promise.
我有好消息  还有坏消息
Got some good news and bad news.
说好消息
Good news.
尼格玛查了一下  找到了一家
Nygma did some digging, found one company
哥谭市内生产液态氦的公司
in all of Gotham that makes liquid helium.
韦恩集团
Wayne Enterprises.
这就是好消息吗
That's the good news?
不是  但"坏消息和更坏的消息"
It's not. But I thought "Bad news and more bad news"
说起来没那么上口
didn't have the same ring.
这是什么
What's this?
上月三起绑架案  都跟一辆蓝色货车有关
Three abductions in the past month all tied to a blue van.
跟嫌犯的车一样
Same as our suspect.
三起绑架案
Three abductions?
有找到人质吗
They find any of 'em?
一个也没有  所以不禁让人怀疑
Not a one, which makes you wonder
这家伙把那些人拿去做什么了
what's this guy doing with all those people?
诺拉  我要去工作几小时
Nora? I'm going to work for a few hours.
你有需要就敲几下
Knock if you need anything.
好
Okay.
-爱德  -别看我
- Ed. - Don't look at me.
我不允许跟你说话的
I'm not supposed to be talking to you.
你还好吧
You doing okay?
你看起来有些颓废
You look kind of funky.
我承认  感觉不怎么样
I confess I've felt better.
我能帮上什么忙
Is there anything I can do to help?
我没救了
I'm beyond help.
忘了我吧  朋友
Forget me, my friend.
但如果你能照料我母亲的坟墓
But if you would take care of my mother's grave,
我会感激不尽的
I'd be very grateful.
没事去扫扫墓
If you'd visit occasionally,
告诉她我惦念着她
tell her I'm thinking of her.
我会的
I will.
她喜欢百合
She likes lilies.
偶尔去上坟  带上百合花  记住了
Occasional visits, lilies, check.
谢谢
Thank you.
站起来  科波特
On your feet, Cobblepot.
怎么回事
What's going on?
你带我去哪里
Where are you taking me?
阿卡姆疯人院
Arkham.
你不是疯了吗
You are insane, right?
今天是2月21号  周四
It is now Thursday, February 21,
下午3点44分
3:44 P.M.
014号实验对象40岁左右
Test subject 014 is in his 40s,
身体看起来很健康
appears to be in good health,
在玻璃化冷冻期间并未遭受损坏
and shows no signs of damage sustained during vitrification.
我准备开始进行复苏实验了
I'm now ready to commence the reanimation experiment.
没错
You are correct.
韦恩集团的确制造液态氦
Wayne Enterprises does manufacture liquid helium.
多年来  一直用于低温项目研究
For years, it was used as part of our cryogenics program.
低稳项目
Cryowhatics?
是物理学中专门研究超低温度的
It's the branch of physics dealing with the production
实现和其效应的分支
and effects of extremely low temperatures.
据我所知  项目的研究进程中有几次实验
My understanding is that there were some promising experiments
取得了不错的结果
being carried out in the program,
但项目还是被叫停了
but, alas, it was shut down.
那是什么时候的事
When was that?
两三年前
Two or three years ago.
托马斯·韦恩中止了该研究
Thomas Wayne killed it,
还有其他几个稀奇古怪的项目
along with a few other odd programs.
知道为什么吗
Any idea why?
不知道
No idea.
这一切都是秘密进行的
It was all kept very quiet.
谢谢  卢修斯
Thanks, Lucius.
二位客气
Detectives.
看  企鹅派
Look! Penguin pie!
好像存在一些误解
There seems to be some confusion.
我的名字...
My name...
叫奥斯瓦尔德·科波特
is Oswald Cobblepot.
不用说  你们很多人
Many of you, no doubt,
都听过我的名字
will have heard of me.
有些人显然没听说过
Some of you, clearly, have not.
对于那些可怜
For those poor,
无知的人  我愿为你们解惑
ignorant souls, I offer illumination.
我可不是好惹的
I am not a man to be trifled with.
不
Oh, no.
我很强大
I am powerful.
我很凶狠
I am vicious!
我是哥谭之王
I'm King of Gotham.
他以为自己是哥谭之王
He thinks he's the king of Gotham.
我是哥谭之王
I'm King of Gotham!
不  我才是哥谭之王
No, I'm the king of Gotham!
我是王  是我  是我
I'm king. I am! I am!
去他妈的
Off with his head!
快看我
Look at me!
我是哥谭之王
I'm King of Gotham!
我是王  我是王
I'm king! I'm king!
听啊  听啊
Hear ye! Hear ye!
实验对象核心温度现为3.9度
Subject's core temperature is now 39 degrees.
即将到达临界阈值
We are approaching the critical threshold.
5度
41 degrees.
已经到了5度
We hit 41 degrees.
A41号溶液
Solution A14.
我就知道能行  我就知道
I knew it would work! I knew it!
太棒了  太棒了
Yes, yes, yes, yes, yes!
不
No.
不不不不不
No, no, no, no, no, no, no.
别又这样  别又这样
Not again. Please, not again. No.
诺拉
Nora?
呼吸  诺拉
Breathe, Nora.
我就在这儿  看着我
I'm right here. Look at me.
福米特罗呢
Where's the formitorol?
这是最严重的一次
That was the worst one yet.
那是最后一粒药了
That was the last pill.
你怎么不说
Why didn't you tell me?
对不起
I'm sorry.
我忘记了
I forgot.
我吃了那么多
There's so many.
如果你再次发病
If you have another attack
又没有这种药可吃  你会死的
and you don't have this medication, you could die.
不能再发生这种事了  诺拉
You can't let this happen again, Nora.
怎么
Why?
那有什么要紧吗
Does it matter?
当然要紧
It matters.
我就回来
I'll be back.
帕克医疗
药房
我需要续这个药
I need to get this refilled.
下一位
Next.
我需要续这个药
I need to get this refilled.
有处方吗
Do you have the prescription?
我有药瓶
I have the bottle.
那可不一样啊
That's not the same thing, is it?
拜托  我真的需要续这个药
Please, I just need it refilled.
诺拉·弗莱斯
福米特罗
原始处方上面没说要续药
The original prescription doesn't have a refill order.
如果没说
If it doesn't have a refill order,
我就不能给你续药
I can't refill it.
这药是给我妻子的
This medication is for my wife.
她病了
She's sick.
她很痛苦
She's in pain.
每个进来这里的人都病了或很痛苦
Everyone that comes in here is sick or in pain.
让你的医生给你写新的处方
Have your doctor write a new prescription.
那我才能给你续药
Then I can refill it.
把药给我
Just give me the medication.
不行
No.
-你个混蛋  -滚出去
- You son of a bitch! - Get out!
让他出去
Get him out of here!
快出去  否则我叫警察了
Get out of here before I call the cops,
你个疯子
you kook!
你不该那么做的
You shouldn't have done that.
我会回来的
I'll be back.
再见  奈吉尔
Good-bye, Nigel.
记住我说的
Oh, and, uh, remember what I told you.
非礼勿视  非礼勿为
See no evil, do no evil.
是  先生
Yes, sir.
我会的
I will.
科波特先生
Mr. Cobblepot.
我叫雨果·斯特兰奇
My name is Hugo Strange.
阿卡姆疯人院的精神病专家
Chief of Psychiatry here at Arkham Asylum.
请进
Please come in.
你没听懂
You're not listening.
或许你该顺便买个新助听器
Maybe you should get a new hearing aid while you're here.
福米特罗
Formitorol.
-快  -好
- Now. - Okay.
好
Okay.
都拿去吧
Take it all.
求你  别杀我  求你
Please, don't kill me. Please.
你要我做什么都行
I-I'll do anything you want.
你和你的朋友
You and your friend here...
A16号溶液
要帮我救我妻子
...are going to help save my wife.
不  不
No! No!
打扰
Excuse me.
我需要人帮忙
I'm going to need some help out.
那人刚刚袭击了第九大道的一家药店
Our guy just hit a pharmacy on Ninth.
就这样  把他滑进去
That's it. Just slide him in there.
小心点
Careful.
蓝货车
Blue van.
快走  快离开
Go. Get out of here.
快追
Go, go, go, go, go.
知道了  知道了
I got it! I got it!
停下
Slow down!
阿卡姆疯人院
这是干什么啊
What is this, anyhow?
阿卡姆疯人院
-我是在遭惩罚吗  -不是
- Am I being punished? - Oh, no.
我会见每一位新来的犯人
I make it a point to meet all new inmates.
这是纳新的标准流程
It's part of the intake protocol.
不过我得要求你
Though I will ask you to refrain
今后不要再
from making speeches
站在餐厅桌上讲话了
atop cafeteria tables in the future.
我尽量吧
I'll do my best.
你在这里适应得如何
How has your adjustment been so far?
还好吧
Fine, I suppose.
得了  奥斯瓦尔德
Oh, come now, Oswald.
大转变的时期会给人带来
Periods of great transition can bring on great...
很大压力
stress.
这经历对你来说一定很创伤吧
Surely, this must be a traumatic experience for you.
得了
Please.
跟我的经历相比
This is a pillow fight compared
-这就是枕头大战  -是啊
- to what I've been through. - Yes.
我读过
I have read
你最近的种种磨难
of your tribulations of late.
有人企图取你性命
Attempts on your life.
不得不做个逃犯  苟且偷生
Having to survive being a fugitive.
以及你母亲的死
The death of your mother.
真是多事之秋
Troubled times.
这就是你的临床诊断吗
Is that your clinical diagnosis?
我知道  如果换了我是你
I know that if I were in your position,
我肯定会有些很强烈的情绪
I would be feeling some strong emotions.
愤怒  悲伤
Anger, grief,
甚至后悔
regret even.
后悔什么
For what?
杀了西奥·盖勒文
The murder of Theo Galavan.
就因为盖勒文  我母亲死在了我怀里
My mother died in my arms because of Galavan.
我唯一的后悔
The only thing I regret is that
就是我只能杀他一次
I couldn't kill him more than once.
这样啊
I see.
或许我们下次再接着聊吧
Perhaps we could pick it up right there next time.
我很期待我们共同合作
I so look forward to our work together.
别担心
And don't worry--
我们阿卡姆有不少很强效的
here at Arkham we have a number of intensive
治疗计划
treatment programs.
我万分自信我们能够
I am more than confident that we'll be able
协助你...恢复精神
to facilitate your... rehabilitation.
什么
My what?
恢复精神
Rehabilitation.
毕竟  这就是你来这里的目的
That's why you're here, after all.
治愈你的疾病
To be cured of your sickness.
你病了
You are sick...
不是吗
aren't you?
维克多
Victor?
亲爱的
Honey?
你在下面吗
You down here?
维克多
Victor?
天呐
My God.
Oh, my God.
天呐
帕克医疗公司
监控根本没开
Surveillance system wasn't even on.
那是什么
What's that?
有目击者说  嫌犯拿这个扔了药剂师
Some witnesses saw our guy throw this at the pharmacist.
诺拉·弗莱斯
福米特罗
大概是他的药瓶
It's probably his prescription bottle.
"弗里斯"  诺拉·弗里斯
"Frees." Nora Frees.
他妻子吗
His wife, maybe?
可能吧  但是该叫"弗莱斯"
Yeah, maybe, but it's Fries.
-什么  -是叫"弗莱斯"
- What do you mean? - It's pronounced Fries.
-你怎么知道  -我就是特别会念名字
- How do you know? - I'm really good with names.
不管了  这上面有地址
Whatever. There's an address on here.
我们走吧
Come on, let's go.
哥谭市警局  我们有搜查令
GCPD, we have a search warrant.
女士  别动
Ma'am, don't move.
老天爷
Holy moley.
他告诉我是老鼠
He told me they were mice.
带她离开
Get her out of here.
弗莱斯太太
Mrs. Fries.
诺拉
Nora.
你没事吧
You all right?
奈吉尔
Nigel?
非礼勿视
See no evil,
非礼勿为
do no evil.
非礼勿视
See no evil,
非礼勿为
do no evil.
不  不
No, no!
非礼勿视  非礼勿为
See no evil, do no evil.
我们得找到你丈夫  诺拉
We need to find your husband, Nora.
免得他再伤人
Before he hurts someone else.
我当时在睡觉
I was asleep.
他出门的声音惊醒了我
I woke up when I heard him leave.
我只能告诉你们这么多
That's all I can tell you.
如果你不配合  我们就只能起诉你
If you don't cooperate, we'll be forced to charge you
妨碍司法
with obstruction of justice.
你会进监狱的  诺拉
You're going to jail, Nora.
你明白吧
You get that, right?
我丈夫做了可怕的事
My husband did terrible things.
但他是为我才做了那些可怕的事
But he did those terrible things for my sake.
我要死了
I'm dying.
他想救我
He wants to save me.
我无法形容我是多么抱歉
I can't tell you how sorry I am,
但我不能背叛他
but I can't betray him.
还有一点
One more thing.
你的姓氏怎么发音
What's the correct pronunciation of your last name?
是弗莱斯
It's Fries.
弗莱斯
Fries.
谢谢
Thank you.
我说的吧
Told you.
打扰
Excuse me?
有什么事吗
Yeah, what can I help you with?
我想找戈登警探
I'd like to speak with Detective Gordon, please.
什么事
What for?
我想认罪
I'd like to make a confession.
是我在到处冻人
I'm the man that's been freezing people.
你也是吗
You too, huh?
你是今晚第五个了
That makes five in one night.
肯定是满月  疯子都跑出来了
Must be a full moon.
这样吧  你先跟他们一起坐下
Tell you what-- why don't you have a seat with the others.
-戈登警探马上就出来  -不不
- Detective Gordon, he'll be out in a minute. - No, no,
你不懂
you don't understand, I...
我懂的  坐吧
Oh, I understand. Have a seat.
我死了吗
Am I dead?
有人吗
Hello?
我死了吗
Am I dead?
-别碰我  -我抓住他了
- Don't touch me. - I got him,
- Don't touch me! - I got him.
A16  成功了
A16. It worked.
拿条毯子
Get a blanket.
居然成功了
I can't believe it worked.
不...
No! N...
你...你
You! You!
你
Y...
好了
Okay, all right.
我就来  诺拉
I'm coming for you, Nora.
我这就来救你
I'm coming to save you.
阿卡姆疯人院
新犯人奥斯瓦尔德·科波特
New inmate Oswald Cobblepot
展示出了极度的自恋和自大
exhibits signs of extreme narcissism and megalomania.
而且似乎跟其已逝的母亲有
Also seems to have had a rather unhealthy relationship
不太健康的关系
with his deceased mother.
治疗将包括厌恶疗法
Treatments will include immersive aversion therapy
以及强效精神药物
and radical psychotropics.
印第安山
今晚如何啊  皮博迪女士
How are we this evening, Ms. Peabody?
很忙  灌入F井里的甲醛该换了
Busy. The formaldehyde pump in silo F needs replacing.
那位女纵火犯不肯
Our young lady arsonist refuses to
配合我们的实验
cooperate with our experiments,
跟卡特议员的见面也
and I had to reschedule your appointment
-不得不改期了  -又改期
- with Councilman Carter. - Again?
这都第三次了
It's the third time.
-真无礼  -是啊
- How very rude. - Indeed.
还有这个
And there's this.
看来有人解决了
Seems someone has solved the problem
人体冷冻复苏的难题
of post-cryonic reanimation.
不可能
Oh, nonsense.
这问题我还远远不能解决呢
I'm still years from solving that.
真有趣
Fascinating.
你知道这对我们的项目可能意味着什么吗
Do you realize what this could mean for our program?
这人是谁
Who is this man?
他叫维克多·弗莱斯
His name is Victor Fries.
但报纸已经给了他个称号
But the newspapers have already given him a nickname.
警方搜寻"急冻人先生"
冻僵男子在哥谭市警局停尸房中复活
你好啊  急冻人先生
Hello, Mr. Freeze.